For a long time in western society,
在西方社会的很长一段时间里，
I think education has been rooted in this notion
我认为教育一直根植于这样一种观念，
that in order to know anything truly and well.
即教育是为了真正和很好地了解任何事物。
We have to disconnect the knower from the known.
我们必须切断知者与被知者的联系。
So only the only knowing that gets honored and validated
因此，唯一得到尊重和验证的认识是
is that which is gained at distance,
在远处获得的认识，
we call it objectivity,
我们称之为客观性，
remove the subjective self
将主观的自我
from the thing you're trying to know.
从你试图认知的事物中移除。
Whether that thing be
不管这个东西是
a piece of the physical world  or a literary text
物质世界的一部分，还是文学作品，
or a an episode in history or whatever it may be,
还是历史上的一段插曲，或者不管它是什么，
remove the knower from the known
把知者从被知者身上移开，
and then you can know it truly and well
然后你就可以真正地、很好地认识它，
without any this subjective stuff:
而没有任何主观的东西：
feelings, emotions, beliefs, values,
如在认知这个客观事物中
slopping over onto that objective thing.
浮现而出的感情、情绪、信仰、价值观等。
Well, it turns out in fact that's
事实证明，这是关于
a great myth about human knowing,
人类认知的一个伟大的神话，
nobody has ever known anything at distance.
没有人曾经远距离地认识过什么东东。
And they're all kinds of folks these days
这些天来，
from philosophers of science
来自科学哲学家
and of feminist scholars who can tell you why,
和女权主义学者的各种人都能告诉你为什么，
that's the case.
这是一个案例。
It's turns out that knowing is about
事实证明，认知是
the engagement of the whole human being with the world.
关于整个人类与世界的接触。
And having read the biographies and
在阅读了许多伟大的知识分子的
autobiographies of many great knowers,
传记和自传后，
I have yet to read one where this know
我还没有读到过这样的传记，
where this person wasn't passionately
即这个人对
engaged with whatever it was that
他或她试图认知的东西
he or she was trying to know.
没有热情参与。
Knowing is very hard work
认知是项非常艰苦的工作，
and you wouldn't do it
如果你的整个自我不参与其中，
if the whole self weren't engaged.
你就不是在认知。
So once we understand that
因此，一旦我们理解了
human knowing itself comes out of
人类的认知
the engagement of the
本身来自于
not only the mind but the heart
不仅是头脑，而且是心灵
and the intuitions and the body
直觉和身体与我们在这个世界上
with the thing we're trying to know in the world.
试图认识的事物的接触。
Once we understand that, then we have a rationale for
一旦我们理解了这一点，那么我们就有了
teachers engaging students with these great subjects.
教师让学生与伟大事物交流的理由，
As for people engaging the student's heart,
让学生的心灵参与其中，
engaging the student's body,
让学生的身体参与其中，
engaging the student's mind.
让学生的头脑参与其中。
And for that to happen,
而要做到这一点，
the teacher has to be engaged with the student.
教师必须与学生一起参与其中。
This is teaching and learning.
这就是教和学。
And knowing are relational activities,
认知是关系性的活动，
their communal activities.
是他们的公共活动。
That's an easy thing to say, but in our culture
说起来很容易，但在我们的文化中，
we think of knowing as a very individual activity,
我们认为认知是一种非常个人化的活动，
we think of knowing is something that
我们认为认识是一些非常聪明的人
some very smart person did a long time ago and
在很久以前做的事情，
laid down the facts.
奠定了事实的基础。
And then teaching and learning become the 1 on 1
然后，教学和学习就变成了对
transmission of those facts,
这些事实的1对1的传递，
from someone who's also quite smart
从一个似乎很聪明的人，即教师，
to someone who isn't smart yet, that's the student.
传递给一个还不聪明的人，即学生。
But that's not the way it works.
但这并不是认知的工作方式。
Knowing comes out of communal engagement
认知来自于共同体的参与，
the community of scientists,
科学家的共同体，
the community of literary scholars, whoever it may be.
文学家的共同体，不管是什么共同体的参与。
And good teaching and learning comes out of
良好的教学和学习来自于
replicating that communal engagement.
对这种社区参与的复制。
So that students are interacting with each other,
这样，学生们就会与对方、
with the subject they're trying to learn
与他们试图学习的主题
and with the teacher who's trying to
以及与试图指导整个过程的
shepard that whole process along.
老师进行互动。
I'll tell you who understands this best,
我会告诉你谁最了解这一点，
this may sound like
这可能听起来像是
kind of complicated philosophical stuff.
一种复杂的哲学内容。
But just walk into any kindergarten classroom
但只要走进任何一个幼儿园教室，
and that's where you will see this being done.
你就会看到里面的老师会这样做。
Kindergarten teacher has the kids seated in a circle.
幼儿园老师让孩子们围坐成一个圈。
She's or he is reading the children
老师给孩子们朗读
a story about an elephant.
一个关于大象的故事。
And that elephant is alive in the middle of the room,
这头大象就在房间中间，
in the kid's imagination, they're engaged with
在孩子们的想象中，孩子们与世界上
this part of the world called an elephant.
被称为大象的东西接触。
And through that imaginative engagement with
通过与大象和
the elephant and with each other,
彼此之间的想象性接触，
they're learning this very mysterious thing
他们正在学习这个非常神秘的东西，
called language,
它叫做语言，
called reading language, called writing language,
叫做阅读的语言，叫做写作的语言，
called speaking language.
叫做说话的语言。
Kindergarten teachers know this in their bones.
幼儿园的老师们从骨子里就知道这一点。
I'm baffled as to why we call higher education higher,
我很困惑，为什么我们把高等教育称为高等的，
because by the time we get there
因为当我们到达那里的时候，
we've forgotten all the things
我们已经忘记了
that kindergarten teachers know
幼儿园老师所知道的
about good teaching and learning.
关于良好教学和学习的所有事情。